A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, S-Z FA394
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Vincent, George E.
  - 1922, Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Vin 1, Frame 854, Box 485)
    Canada; England; France; Hygiene; Medical education; Public health; Nursing; Switzerland; Scotland; United States; Peking. Union Medical College; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
  - Exhibits, 1922; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Includes: Memorandum of Interview with Doctor Yen; Conference of ERE with (a) WR, and (b) GEV Concerning Nurse Training; Statement of the Situation of the near East Relief; Memorandum of Interview with Prince Songkla; Confidential Memorandum of an Informal Conference Regarding the George Washington University Situation; Memorandum of Interview with Mr. Waldron H. Rand, Dr. Blanche A. Denig, and Miss Tupper; two Conferences in Greenwich; A Yearbook of Medical Education and Public Health; Notes of Trip June 19th to 21st, 1922; Conference on the Far East; Conference on Medical Education in Europe; Memorandum on the Status and Relationships of the Division of Medical Education.
    Medical education; Public health
  - Index, 1923; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485, Reel M Vin 2, Frame 14)
    1923 Index; 7 pages
  - 1923, Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board (Reel M Vin 2, Frame 21, Box 485)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Board and China Medical Board. The 1923 diary includes a trip to South America and discussions of malaria program options with Argentine officials. Include is a brief biography of Arturo Alessandri.
    Brazil; Bolivia; Hygiene; Chile; Medical education; Malaria; Nursing; Medicine, Preventive; United States; Peru; Public health; Argentina; Peking. Union Medical College
  - Exhibit, January 19, 1923; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485, Reel M Vin 2, Frame 340)
    Exhibit Memorandum of An Informal Conference on Policies of Russian Relief.
  - Transcription, June 13, 1923; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Transcription Follows; Siam-Problems Concerning DME in Relation to IHB; Responsibilities of European Office of Rockefeller Foundation; Examples of Further Work in Europe which may Prove Desirable After Study and Experience on the Ground; Suggested Organization; International Fellowships under Rockefeller Auspices; Memorandum on Extension of Departments of Neurology for Investigation of the Interrelations of Mind and Body in Disease; Memorandum on Medical University Extension; Graduate Medical Education.
  - Index, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Vin 2, Frame 384, Box 485)
    1924 Index; 5 pages
  - 1924, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Reel M Vin 2, Frame 382, Box 485)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Board and China Medical Board. In 1924, Vincent take a trip to the Near East and Jamaica to survey medical education and facilities, determine need of Rockefeller Foundation assistance, and assess program progress.
    Yellow fever; Czechoslovakia; Egypt; England; Hookworm disease; United States; Turkey; Austria; Canada; Nursing; Medical education; Public health; Italy; Hungary; Lebanon; Jamaica; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - Conference, 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains a report on the "Conference on General Matters Pertaining to Nursing Education (in Greenwich).
  - Exhibit, 18-19 January 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Exhibit Memorandum on Conference at Gedney Farms.
  - Interview, 24 February 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Interview with Dr. Keyes and Dr. Hoover.
  - Interview, 25 February 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Interview with Dr. Dorman of Beirut Medical School.
  - Memorandum, 26 February 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Memorandum of Interview with Dr. George H. Washburn representing Robert College.
  - Memorandum, 26 February 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Memorandum of Interview with Dr. Talcott Williams at Phi Beta Kappa dinner, Hotel Astor.
  - Memorandum, 29 February 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Memorandum of Interview with Miss Dorothea Chambers.
  - Memorandum, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Memorandum for Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial.
  - Memorandum, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Memorandum for George E. Vincent New York Dispensary Program.
  - Conference, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
  - Proposal, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Proposed English-Speaking Institute in Japan.
  - Interview, 1924; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 485)
    Interview with Dr. Wilinsky.
  - Conference Memorandum, 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Memorandum for conference with Mr. Debevoise concerning agreements with medical schools.
  - Report, 13 November 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Report of Office Conference.
  - Resume, 26 December 1924; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 485)
    Grosvenor, William Mason.
    Engineering; Physical sciences
  - Index, 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    1925 Index; 6 pages
  - 1925 January-July, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486, Reel M Vin 2, Frame 771)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Board and China Medical Board. In 1925, Vincent attends various conferences and discusses RF projects with officers. With Index.
    Hygiene; Malaria; Medical education; Nursing; Public health; United States; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - Interview, 3 January 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Interview- Colonel Parsons, Mr. Coykendall, Doctor Rose, Doctor Vincent and Mr. Flexner
  - Conference, 30 January 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Office Conference on Various Questions Relating to Fellowships.
  - Budget Committee, 4 May 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Budget Committee; 3 pages.
  - Notes, 28 January 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Notes Upon Conference- Sao Paulo.
    Public health; Medical education; Brazil
  - Budget Committee, 25 February- 9 April 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Budget Committee; Meetings of President, Secretary, representatives of Comptroller's Office and departmental boards and divisions.
  - Meeting, 11 March 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    National Health Conservation Minutes of Meeting.
  - Budget Committee, 13 April 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Budget Committee.
  - Conference, 22 April 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Office Conference; 4 pages.
  - Conference, 5 May 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Office Conference.
  - Budget Committee, 8 May 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Interview, 1 June 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Interview with Mrs. E.I. Vaughn.
  - Conference, 10 June 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Conference Nursing Education as a Foundation Field.
    Public health; Medical education; Nursing
  - Exhibit, 30 June 1925; American Red Cross; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Exhibit: League of Red Cross Societies page 1952.
  - Budget Committee, 2 July 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Notes of Meeting, 17 July 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Notes of Meeting.
  - Budget Committee, 8 December 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Paris Office Meeting, 20-24 July 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Paris Office meetings regarding public health and nursing.
    Public health; Medical education; Nursing; France
  - Budget Committee, 30 July 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - 1925 August-December, Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board (Box 486, Reel M Vin 2, Frame 963)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Board and China Medical Board. In 1925, Vincent attends various conferences and discusses RF projects with officers. With Exhibit.
    England; Hygiene; Hospitals; Nursing; Medical education; United States; Public health; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - Exhibit, 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar)
    Contains program for the League of Red Cross Societies.
    Nursing; England
  - Memo, 24-25 August 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Memo of Interviews Miss Goodrich and Miss Clayton.
  - Conference, 5-12 October 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    The Rockefeller Foundation Conference on Aims' Policies and Programs in Nurse Training.
    Nursing; Medical education; Public health
  - Budget Committee, 30 July-9 October 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Budget Committee Meetings.
  - Recommendations, 20 October 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Recommendations of the Conference on Nursing Education.
    Medical education; Nursing; Public health
  - Budget Committee, 23 October 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 1 December 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 29 December 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
  - Conference, 16 December 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Interboard Conference on Mental Hygiene, Psychology, Psychiatry.
    Hygiene; Medical education; Mental health; Psychiatry; Psychology; Public health
  - Diary: Gladys E. Russell, 27 March-21 December 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Diary:Gladys E. Russell.
  - Memorandum, 1925; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Medical education; Europe; United States; Public health
  - Conference, 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    The First International Conference of Social Work, Paris.
  - Exhibit, 1925; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Exhibit page 149.
  - Report, 1925; General Education Board. (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    General Education Board: Report of the Special Committee on policy with respect to state support institutions.
  - Registration, 1924-1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Registration in Schools of Hygiene.
    Public health; Medical education; Hygiene
  - Index, 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486, Reel M Vin 3, Frame 14)
    1926 Index; 6 pages.
  - 1926, Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Peking. Union Medical College; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486, Reel M Vin 3, Frame 20)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, International Health Board and China Medical Board. In 1926, Vincent travels to Europe to survey medical education and facilities. The during this time aids medical schools, maintains Peking Union Medical College, assists in public health training development, and contributes to nursing education. The diary includes Rev. Eliot White's business card.
    Nursing; Montenegro; Public health; Italy; Hygiene; Medical education; Malaria; England; Croatia; Hookworm disease; France; Serbia; United States; Canada; Austria
  - Office Conference, 5 January 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation. Agricultural Sciences (Box 486)
  - Conference, 6 January 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Conference with Dr. Alice Hamilton of the Harvard School of Public Health and of the Health Committee of the League of Nations, and FFR.
  - Committee Meeting, 17 January 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Agenda Central Committee Meeting.
  - Committee, 18 February 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Office Space for Rockefeller Boards Resume of Report of Joint Committee.
  - Meeting, 23 February 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Annual Meeting C.R.B. Educational Foundation, Inc.
  - Report, 29 February 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Public health; Medical education; Physics; Biology -- Research; Chemistry
  - Docket Conference, 1926; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Rockefeller Foundation; Cowdry, E. V. (Edmund Vincent) (Box 486)
    Docket Conference (CMB).
  - Budget Committee, 10 May 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Budget Committee
  - Budget Committee, 13 May 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 14 May 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 24 May 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 22 June 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Budget Committee, 27 September 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
  - Agenda, 4 October 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Agenda for Interboard Luncheon.
  - Budget Committee, 15 October 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
  - Programs, 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
    Programs of the Rockefeller Boards in France.
    France; Medical education; Public health
  - Diary: Gladys E. Russell, 15 February-17 November 1926; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 486)
  - Faculty Expenses, 1926; Peking. Union Medical College; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    Peking Union Medical College (Education Expenses for Faculty).
  - List, 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    List of Items to Discuss with GEV.
    Public health; Biology -- Research; Hospitals; Medical education; Nursing
  - Agenda, 1926; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 486)
    For Office Conference Agenda.
  - Index, 1927; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Vin 3, Frame 418, Box 486)
    1927 Index; 6 pages.
  - 1927 (Box 487, Reel M Vin 3, Frame 426)
  - Diary: Gladys E. Russell, 10 January-23 December 1927; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 487)
  - Index, 1928; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Vin 3, Frame 792, Box 487)
    1928 Index; 6 pages.
  - 1928, Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Peking. Union Medical College (Reel M Vin 3, Frame 798, Box 487)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, and International Health Board. The Rockefeller Foundation has switch goals in in 1928. The Foundation is focusing on public health and advancement of knowledge in medical, natural, and social sciences as well as humanities.
    Public health; Medical education; United States; Switzerland; England; Hygiene; France
  - Exhibits, 1928; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Box 487)
    Exhibits include: Preliminary Outline for the Study of Scholarly Publications; Lectures, Suggestions Regarding Training of Nurses for Public Health, Agenda for Staff Conference, Conference Between Mr. Trevor Arnett and RMP September 12, 1925 Concerning Problems of the GEB in Relation to the RF; Conference- September 17, 1928, General Conference, October 5, 1928; China Medical Board, Inc.; General Conference, 19, 1928, General Conference, October 31, 1928- 11A.M.; Staff Conference November 7, 1928; Joint Meeting of the Divisional Committees; Office Conference November 12, 1928; Office Conference Activities under Consideration; The Advancement of Knowledge; For Office Conference, December 6, 1928; Minutes of Office Conference December 6, 1928; Rockefeller Foundation Activities Under Consideration; Staff Conference December 17, 1928 Minutes;December 21, 1928 Staff Conference
  - Index, 1929; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar) (Box 487, Reel M Vin 3, Frame 1,190)
    1929 Index; 5 pages.
  - 1929, Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Vin 3, Box 487)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Vincent talks to various professionals in the field of public health and discusses projects and proposals. As President of the Rockefeller Foundation he is involved in the institutional and administrative duties of the Rockefeller Foundation, and International Health Board.
  - Diary: Gladys E. Russell, 1929 January 3-September 18; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar); Rockefeller Foundation
  - Conference, 1925 January 28; Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar)
    Contains "Notes upon Conference - Sao Paulo".
  - Memorandum, Rockefeller Foundation; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar)
    Contains "Memorandum of a Conference: Training of Nurses in Europe and the U.S., etc."
    Nursing
- Walcott, Allen M.
  - 1931-1932 (Box 488)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 488)
  - 1935-1937 (Box 488)
- Walker, Sydnor H.
  Sydnor H. Walker worked with the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (LSRM) and the Rockefeller Foundation's (RF) Division of the Social Sciences, helping to shape research in the social sciences over the course of two decades.
  Walker was born in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1891. She received an A.B. in economics from Vassar College in 1913 and an M.A. from the University of Southern California in 1917.
  She returned to Vassar in 1917, where she served as an instructor in economics. A colleague commented that Walker was appreciated by the students for "her quick wit and gaiety...although she could be sharply critical of the careless and the dilatory."[1] In 1919 Walker left her teaching position to join an industrial relations consulting firm headed by Beardsley Ruml. She subsequently went abroad to Vienna and Russia to aid in European relief with the American Friends Service Committee.
  Upon her return to the U.S. in 1924, Walker was recruited by Ruml to work for the LSRM as a research associate. She was a staunch advocate of using scientific and standardized methods to conduct research in the social sciences. While working for the LSRM, Walker continued her studies at Columbia University, receiving her Ph.D. in economics in 1928. Her dissertation, "Social Work and the Training of Social Workers," was published by the University of North Carolina Press in 1928.
  When many of LSRM's programs were consolidated with the RF in 1929 and a new Division of the Social Sciences created, Walker became Assistant Director of the division. She was promoted to Associate Director in 1933 and Acting Director in 1937. Among her interests at the RF, she was a proponent of improving the teaching of social work and the administration of social welfare programs. Her grant-making extended to many southern universities. She also contributed to the development of the social sciences outside the U.S., working with grantees in Europe and Latin America.
  Resigning from the RF in 1943 for health reasons, she worked on a report for the Woodrow Wilson Foundation, "The First Hundred Days of the Atomic Age," which was published in 1945.
  She served as a trustee for Vassar College from 1939-1943 and was appointed assistant to the president of Vassar College in 1948, a position she held until 1957.
  Sydnor H. Walker passed away in 1966.
  [1] Josephine Gleason et al. "Sydnor Harrison Walker: A Memorial Minute," Vassar Faculty Meeting, December 1966, Biographical Files Collection, Vassar College Archives, Vassar Libraries.
  - Appendix, 1925-1926; Walker, Sydnor Harbison (Reel M Wal 1, Frame 1, Box 489)
    This Appendix lists the dates, institutions, and names of individuals interviewed by Miss Walker between 1925 and 1926.
  - 1925 October-December, Walker, Sydnor Harbison (Box 489, Reel M Wal 1, Frame 8)